<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>07 - 3D Printing on Modeling and Fabrication</title>
    <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/07-3d-printing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 07 - 3D Printing on Modeling and Fabrication</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/07-3d-printing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7.3 3D Test Print Photo Documentation</title>
      <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/07-3d-printing/7-3-3d-test-print-photo-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/07-3d-printing/7-3-3d-test-print-photo-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;flex-container-jimmy&#34; style=&#34;display: flex; align-items: top; flex-wrap: wrap; margin-top: 0; margin-bottom: 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;half-box&#34; style=&#34;flex: 1 1 400px; margin-top: 0; margin-bottom: 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a minimum of two photos of your 3D Test Print. Take one from a 3/4 angle that shows a good representation of the form. Take the other from a composition of your choice. This could show some detail of the print. Make sure the print is in focus. Using a camera from the checkout with a zoom feature will help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up lights and a clean backdrop. You can check out lights and a camera from the CIA equipment checkout. You can also take your model to the think[box] and use the soft boxes and flashes already set up. Shoot in JPG and RAW and post process the images. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m0yZEWUSahk&#34;&gt;White balance should be corrected&lt;/a&gt; and the levels should be adjusted to have good exposure. Use Photoshop and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=11jwSwUu2WI&#34;&gt;Adobe Camera Raw&lt;/a&gt; to make adjustments and to retouch any mistakes in the images. Label the photos YYYYMMDD 3D Test Print&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take 2 Photos with a clean backdrop of your 3D Test Print.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Label the photos YYYYMMDD Lastname Firstname 3D Test Print Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use good lighting and shoot in JPG and RAW so you can edit and post process your images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload the images to Google Drive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1mXIp3dATl6tbCALPdLgeSXYw9KrEn-1N&#34;&gt;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1mXIp3dATl6tbCALPdLgeSXYw9KrEn-1N&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;half-box&#34; style=&#34;flex: 1 1 400px; margin-top: 0; margin-bottom: 0;&#34;&gt;![](/ICS/icsfs/mm/2022_camera_cheat_sheet.png?target=712bb5a6-8149-4c54-9105-d1f671924389)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tutorial-videos&#34;&gt;Tutorial Videos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-grid&#34; style=&#34;display: grid; align-items: end; grid-template-columns: repeat(auto-fit, minmax(300px, 1fr)); grid-gap: 1rem;&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34; style=&#34;border: 1px solid grey; display: flex; flex-direction: column; height: 100%; justify-content: space-between; margin: 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-any-image-in-camera-raw&#34;&gt;Open Any Image in Camera Raw&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;youtube-box&#34; style=&#34;position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0px; padding-top: 56.25%; margin-top: 0; margin-bottom: 0;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-iframe&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: 0; z-index: 1;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ftMICesJwGc?rel=0&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34; style=&#34;border: 1px solid grey; display: flex; flex-direction: column; height: 100%; justify-content: space-between; margin: 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-white-balance-in-photoshop&#34;&gt;Quick White Balance in Photoshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;youtube-box&#34; style=&#34;position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0px; padding-top: 56.25%; margin-top: 0; margin-bottom: 0;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-iframe&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: 0; z-index: 1;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m0yZEWUSahk?rel=0&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34; style=&#34;border: 1px solid grey; display: flex; flex-direction: column; height: 100%; justify-content: space-between; margin: 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;camera-raw-tutorial&#34;&gt;Camera Raw Tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;youtube-box&#34; style=&#34;position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0px; padding-top: 56.25%; margin-top: 0; margin-bottom: 0;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-iframe&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; bottom: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border: 0; z-index: 1;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/11jwSwUu2WI?rel=0&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading-rubric&#34;&gt;Grading Rubric&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Assessment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Weight&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Photo 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Photo 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;File Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7.4 Final 3D Print Ideation Sketches</title>
      <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/07-3d-printing/7-4-final-3d-print-ideation-sketches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/07-3d-printing/7-4-final-3d-print-ideation-sketches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;3d-print-design-and-fabrication-project&#34;&gt;3D Print Design and Fabrication Project&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have made a test 3D print and are more familiar with the opportunities and challenges of 3D printing, we will tackle specific design challenges using the 3D printing fabrication process. You make need to make additional small test print “proof of concepts” to get your final idea to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;design-challenges&#34;&gt;Design Challenges&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often creative work has arbitrary restrictions on the creative process. There may be challenges based on material availability, budget, time, aesthetic criteria and countless other constraints on what you can make. Part of your job as an artist and designer is to work around these restraints and still create new and compelling creative works of culture. For this project choose one or more of the design challenges below. How can you meet the criteria of the challenge(s) and still make unique and exciting objects?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-an-extension-of-the-body&#34;&gt;Make an extension of the body&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you need a helmet? A headband? What about flexible knuckle guards? Does your hand need and custom fit extension for scraping ice off of windshields? To complete this challenge, articulate a problem to solve with a body extension. This can be functional, decorative or both. How does the 3D print solve the problem? Measure your body or the target person’s body and use these dimensions as guideposts when modeling in Fusion 360.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;combine-3d-printing-and-laser-cutting&#34;&gt;Combine 3D Printing and Laser cutting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3D printing is a great technology, but it has limitations. Laser cutting is also wonderful but has its own set of restrictions. Combine the two technologies to create something that would not be possible with a single technique or fabrication process. You could incorporate brackets to attach laser cut panels at angle or to create a shelf.  You could design a phone or laptop stand with 3D printed hinges, so it is more functional.  Laser cutting can be a quick way to add scale to your 3D prints and 3D printing can add versatility of connection and position other than 90 degrees to your laser cuts. Design with the best of both worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-a-print-in-place-flexible-joint&#34;&gt;Use a Print in Place Flexible Joint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 3D printing objects can be created that would not be possible with other fabrication techniques. One such method is a print in place hinge or joint. Print it place means that the two separate objects are printed “in [place” or as is on the 3D print bed. Once completed the two parts are forever locked together. Can you make a movable ball and socket figure or snake? What about designing an adjustable cellphone tripod holder for documenting work? Hinges for a box lid?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fit-a-real-world-objects&#34;&gt;Fit a real world object(s)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 3D prints to have a function beyond decoration they must interact with the environment. Often that means attaching to a specific object or enclosing a specific object. For this design challenge use digital calipers to measure an object from the world. Then design a 3D print to add functionality or decoration or both to the object. Does your pencil need a top hat wearing rubber ducky that fits on top? Need a custom headphone holder for your desk?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-an-interlocking-lid&#34;&gt;Have an interlocking lid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boxes are great. What is better than a box? A box with an interlocking, perfectly fitting lid is better. Even better is a box with an interlocking lid that has a hinge and a clasp to keep it closed. Design a custom box that has a lid. What should it contain? Think of things that don’t have premade boxes. Is there a board game that you play that could usea box to contain specific pieces?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-dimension-over-7&#34;&gt;One dimension over 7”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the nature of 3D printing, prints are often small. For this design challenge you need to make a 3D print with at least one dimension over 8”.  The interior build size of the Ultimaker 2+ 3D printer at the think[box] is 8.1” (20.5 cm) tall, 8.8” (22.3 cm) wide, 8.8” (22.3 cm) deep. Getting a print over 7” in one dimension is running right up to the limits of the build volume. What about putting the print in diagonally? Can multiple pieces be connected together for a print that is larger than the machine itself? What other creative ways can you increase the size of y our 3D print?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-custom-lego-compatible-pieces&#34;&gt;Make Custom Lego Compatible Pieces&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lego is fun but Lego is still an extant company with trademarks, patents and copyrights. Luckily the standard building block is no longer protected by patent. Anyone can make an exactly matching dimensioned toy building block. What you can’t do is call it Lego or copy existing Lego designs. That still leaves a universe of creative possibilities. What can you make out of interlocking building blocks? Can you improve on the design? Can you make your own design for toy block figures? Go crazy but only make your own original content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sculpt-in-a-3d-sculpting-program&#34;&gt;Sculpt in a 3D Sculpting Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Mudbox, installed on the lab computers, or Blender or Z-brush or other 3D sculpting program to make a detailed 3D sculpture that would not be possible with polygon modeling. Export the sculpture as an .obj file for further import and parametric modeling in Fusion 360 or export as an STL file for direct printing. If you use this technique of digital sculpting, you should intentionally make something that could not be make with polygon modeling or solid parametric modeling alone. Consider combining sculpting techniques with a parametrically modeled base or support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ideation-sketches&#34;&gt;Ideation Sketches&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using thumbnail sketches, quickly design numerous ideas tackling the design challenges above. The ideation phase is one of the most important parts of the design process. Push yourself to generate unique and developed ideas.  Thumbnail sketches should take 4-7 minutes each for a total of 40 – 70 minutes of thumbnail sketching. Refined sketching should take 5-10 minutes each for a total of 25 – 50 minutes of refined sketching. The final revised sketch should take 10-20 minutes. Total ideation time should be 75 to 140 minutes. That is not a lot of time in the creative process, but it is important time. It shows in the quality and depth of your sketches if you do not take this time to ideate fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you finish your sketches scan them and upload them to the class Google Drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;required-sketches&#34;&gt;Required Sketches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 thumbnail sketches minimum - These should be 10 different ideas. Draw without constraint. Do not limit your ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 larger refined ideations minimum - Choose some of your ideas from your thumbnails. Refine them and iterate on the concepts. Which parts do you like and which parts can you change to make your ideas better?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 larger refined drawing - Pick one of the 5 developed sketches and continue to refine it and change it. Draw it larger in perspective. You can add shading and details to help communicate your vision and solution to the design challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;prepare-your-files&#34;&gt;Prepare your Files&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;export-stl-file-for-3d-test-print&#34;&gt;Export STL file for 3D Test Print&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the video on the tutorial page to export your model as an STL file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose File &amp;gt; 3D Print to save your STL Label the file YYYYMMDD Lastname Firstname 3D Print Project Print.stl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;export-f3d-file-of-model-from-fusion-360&#34;&gt;Export .f3d file of Model from Fusion 360&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose File &amp;gt; Export &amp;hellip; and save a .f3d version of your object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apply-materials-and-export-a-render-image&#34;&gt;Apply materials and Export a Render Image&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3D print will be a solid color of PLA plastic or ABS plastic at the DOC or many different multicolors from the industrial printers at the think[box]. Choose a color and apply that material to your model. Set up a render scene with a 1:1 or 16:9 or 2:3 aspect ratio. Make one of the dimensions a minimum of 4000px. Export a render image with a good composition. Don&amp;rsquo;t make the object too small in the image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;upload-to-google-drive&#34;&gt;Upload to Google Drive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upload the following items to Google Drive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scans of your ideation sketches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STL file of model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.f3d file of model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;render image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading-rubric&#34;&gt;Grading Rubric&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Assessment&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Weight&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 thumbnails&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 revised sketches&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;final sketch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fusion Model&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Render Image&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;STL Export&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sketch Documentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;File Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>