<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modeling and Fabrication</title>
    <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Modeling and Fabrication</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Description</title>
      <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Digital II builds technical proficiency and critical thinking about the role of digital technology. The course offers a common core that reviews file management and digital workflows, covers video editing, time-based images, narrative structures, 3D output of assets from digital models, and forms digital literacy in relation to vocabulary, resources, and digital research. Students will gain experience with basic coding, interactivity, and go more in depth into a particular topic in their chosen track. Course structure consists of introductory concept lectures, technical instruction, lab time with guidance and group critique of finished assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;digital-ii-modeling-and-fabrication&#34;&gt;Digital II: Modeling and Fabrication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital II: Modeling and Fabrication is a course that introduces foundational digital 3D applications and methods. Focus will be on 3D output including digital options and physical options. Various methods covered will include using CNC, laser cutters, casting/mold making, 3D printing, VR/AR, and Computer Graphics. Course structure consists of introductory concept lectures, technical instruction, lab time with guidance and group critique of finished assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-goals-and-objectives--upon-completion-of-the-course-students-will-have-to-opportunity-to&#34;&gt;Learning Goals and Objectives – Upon completion of the course, students will have to opportunity to:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think critically about the role of digital technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieve technical proficiency at a foundational level in various relevant software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply Digital Literacy at a foundational level in relation to semantics, digital resources, and digital research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply foundation principles with Digital Tools in 2D, 3D and 4D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage and organize files and digital workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit Video for animation and narrative structures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage 3D output of assets from digital models, either 2D vector or 3D mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand variables and functions in computer code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code for animation or algorithmic painting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize 3D software and understand the basics of 3D modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use digital software to create physical objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiment with other digital output for 3D including VR/AR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create innovative 3D sculptures and models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate the advantages/disadvantages of using digital technology in 3D form&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand and apply design principles using digital technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Modules</title>
      <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/resources/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>