<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>11 - CNC on Modeling and Fabrication</title>
    <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/11-cnc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 11 - CNC on Modeling and Fabrication</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/11-cnc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>11.4 CNC Project Documentation</title>
      <link>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/11-cnc/4-4-cnc-project-dcoumentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://whatmakeart.com/modeling-and-fabrication/modules/11-cnc/4-4-cnc-project-dcoumentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;documentation-photos-of-cnc-projects&#34;&gt;Documentation Photos of CNC Projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you cut out, assemble and finish your CNC project to your satisfaction, take documentation photographs of your work. Having good documentation of your creative work is essential and is an important part of the creative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Take a minimum of 4 Photos that show all aspects of your project. **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should show the overall form, the construction details and any other relevant views that will give a viewer a complete understanding of you piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-a-camera-not-your-cell-phone&#34;&gt;Use a Camera NOT your Cell Phone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out a DSLR or Mirrorless digital camera from the Checkout at CIA. You can also checkout lights. If lights are unavailable, taking photos outdoors in daylight is a good alternative. DO NOT take indoor photographs with poor light, a single light source, or with the flash from your cell phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your cell phone may take ok pictures outdoors in the sunshine but that is about the only time. You are unable to change the depth of field with a cell phone camera. Use the good cameras available to you for free from the checkout at CIA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-lights-or-take-outside-in-daytime&#34;&gt;Use Lights or Take Outside in Daytime&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use at least two light sources spaced apart from the object pointed in at 45 degrees. This will create relatively even lighting and show the structure of your piece. Having a single light from the camera or behind the camera will not look good. Use two lights, each off to the sides of the camera pointed at the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not have two lights, then you can take your photos outdoors. The sun is a great light source. A cloudy day can be used to get soft shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;have-a-clean-distraction-free-background&#34;&gt;Have a Clean, Distraction Free Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The background should not distract from your project. It is best to shoot in front of a photo sweep. Good photos can be made in front of walls or out in the open. The key is not having a busy background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use a shallow depth of field on the camera. Open the aperture wide and focus on your object. The background will then be blurry and your object will stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are outdoors, a brick or concrete wall can work well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have your object too close to any walls either indoors or outdoors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit Photos in Photoshop for Levels and White Balance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All photos can be improved through post production. Make sure you adjust the levels of your photos to bring out all the detail and dynamic range for bright whites and dark blacks. Adjust the white balance so the colors look good. You can use the eye dropper in the levels tool of Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;label-your-images&#34;&gt;Label your images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Label your images YYYYMMDD Lastname Firstname CNC Project Documentation Photos.jpg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not leave them with the default file names from your camera such as IMG_3592.JPG&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;upload-to-google-drive&#34;&gt;Upload to Google Drive&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>